本字幕由Norm HALFCD Team倾情制作
感谢原作提供资源.本作品仅供学习交流.严禁用于商业行为
请自觉于下载后24小时内删除!如果喜欢本片,请购买正版!
更多精彩 尽在www.NormTeam.com
压制:鬼谷子  字幕:鬼谷子
Compression:GV-Sir  Subtitles:GV-Sir
感谢圣城字幕组以下人员
翻译：岸  Dean 春天的豆豆熊  呀嘿呀嘿呀嘿  小FA  Christian
协调：岸 校对：甜蜜的向往  岸
这就是我的一天
Here's my day,so far.
蹲过监狱 失去我爱的女孩 还被臭打了一顿
Went to jail,lost the girl of my dreams and got my butt kicked.
很好
Pretty good.
情况可能会更糟糕
Still,things could be a lot worse.
对了 我马上要摔死了
Oh,that's right,I'm falling to my death.
不是吧
Guess they can't.
你会问 这是怎么回事?
How did it all come to this,you ask?
我的结局在开始就被注定
My end starts at the beginning.
从出生开始
The very beginning.
没错 那就是我
Yes,that's me.
我有过短暂但正常的"童"年
I had a fairly standard childhood.
我出身在一个通常所说的 破碎的家庭
I came from what you might call,a broken home.
破碎是字面上的
Literally,broken.
出生八天后就再也没见过父母
I was eight days old and still living with my parents.
有够悲催的吧?
How sad is that?
命运齿轮开始转动
Clearly it was time to move on.
这是Minion 它会照顾你
Here is your,Minion,he will take care of you.
拿好你的奶嘴
And here is your binkie.
你命中注定会...
You are destined for ...
我没听清最后半句
I didn't quite hear that last part.
貌似很重要
But it sounded important.
命中注定 干什么?
Destined for,what?
我出发去寻找命运
I set out to find my destiny.
看来另一个来自蓝宝象限的孩子也这么想
Turns out a kid from the Blaupunkt quadrant had the exact same idea.
那天我遇见 "比别人都强" 先生
That was the day I met,Mr.Goody-two-shoes.
咱们的最佳对手竞争拉开了序幕
And our glorious rivalry,was born!
啊 这就是我的命运?
Could this be what I was destined for?
如梦如幻的奢华生活?
A dream life filled with luxury?
显然不是
Apparently not.
就连命运也挑喜欢的
Even fate picks its favorites.
没什么大不了
No big deal.
一个截然不同的未来等着我
A much different fate awaited me.
是小宝宝哎
A baby.
考虑太周到了
How thoughtful.
没错 我看见他就想起你
Oh yes,yes.I saw it and thought of you.
总算有个小地方是我家了
Luckily I found a lovely little place to call home.
我们可以养他吗?
Can we keep it?
那里教我什么是对...
A place that taught me the differences between right...
...什么是错
...and wrong.
而 "比别人都强" 先生
Mr.Goody-Two-Shoes on the other hand,
衣来伸手 饭来张口
had life handed to him on a silver platter.
咱家的宝宝会飞哎
Our baby can fly.
没错 你的都是最好的 亲爱的
Yes,yes.Nothing but the best for you,Darling.
他有飞行力 刀枪不入 发型也不错
The power of flight,invulnerability,and great hair.
但有项我比他强的多
But I had something far,far greater,
那就是聪明才智
My amazing intellect.
我能把犯罪工具造得出神入化
A knack for building objects of mayhem.
几年后 因为表现良好
After a few years,and with some time off for good behavior.
我被允许上学来改造自己
I was given an opportunity to better myself through learning.
那个奇怪的地方叫学 "笑"
At a strange place called shh-ool.
在那里我又遇到了 "比别人都强" 先生
It was there that I once again ran into Mr.Goody-Two-Shoes.
显然他已经有N个没脑子的仰慕者了
He had already amassed a gigantic army of soft-headed groupies.
他靠生动表演和香喷喷的米花 讨大家喜欢
He bought their affections with showmanship,and extravagant gifts of deliciousness.
哼 看我的 "爆玉米花" 让这群呆子大吃一惊
So I too would make this 'popped-corn' and win over those mindless dregs.
熄灯了!
Lights out!
那次我学到了艰难的一课
That's when I learned a very hard lesson.
英雄生来满载赞扬和奉承
Good receives all the praise and adulation.
坏蛋就活该面壁思过
While evil is sent to quiet time in the corner.
于是我注定无法跟别人相处
So a fitting end wasn't really an option.
当他们在学可爱小蜘蛛时
While they were learning the itsy bitsy spider.
我学会怎么给活物脱水
I learned how to dehydrate animate objects.
和怎样任意再水化它们
and rehydrate them at will.
有时感觉只有Minion和我在一起 与全世界为敌
Some days it felt like it was just me and Minion,against the world.
不管怎么努力
No matter how hard I tried.
我永远都不合群
I was always the odd man out.
是剩下的那个
The last one picked.
永远一团糟 是害群之马
The screw-up,the black sheep.
是不良少年
The bad boy.
哦!
Oh!
这就是我的命运?
Was this my destiny?
等等!也许没错
Wait!Maybe it was.
当坏蛋不就是我最擅长的吗
Being bad is the one thing I'm good at.
我恍然大悟
Then it hit me.
如果我是个坏孩子
If I was the bad boy.
我就要坏到彻底
Then I was going to be the baddest boy of them all.
我注定会成为超级大坏蛋
I was destined to be a super villain.
我们注定是对手
And we were destined to be rivals.
命运就这样决定了
The die had been cast.
我的永恒史诗 毕生事业就此拉开序幕
And so began an enduring epic,life long career.
我爱这项事业
And I loved it.
我们的战斗很快变得越来越复杂
Our battles quickly got more elaborate.
他赢几次 我也不甘示弱
He would win some,I would almost win others.
他有个大名 都市侠
He took the name,Metro Man.
大都会守卫者
Defender of Montrosity.
我的名字呢 就谦卑多了
I decided to pick something a little more humble.
超级大坏蛋
Megamind.
史上最帅犯罪天才 精通各种恶行
Incredibly handsome criminal genius,and master of all villainy.
下班了再看 开门
Read on your own time.Open up.
嗨
Hey!
嘘
BOO!!
早上好 典狱长
Oh,good morning,Warden.
好消息哦 我改过自新了
Great news,I'm a changed man.
作为可靠市民 我可以重返社会了
And I'm ready to re-enter society as a solid citizen.
你是个罪犯 而且永远是个罪犯
You're a villain,and you'll always be a villain.
你根本没有改过
You'll never change.
也就别想着离开
And you'll never leave.
- 你真搞笑 - 有人给你邮了份礼物
-You're fun. - You got a present in the mail.
是小狗吗?
Is it a puppy?
都市侠给你的 "珍惜你85次无期徒刑的每分每秒吧"
From Metro Man.To count every second of your 85 life sentences.
真搞笑 没想到都市侠也会落井下石
That's funny,never thought Metro Man was the gloating type.
但他品位确实不错
Oh but he does have nice taste.
我帮你保管吧
I think I'll keep it.
能不能别再拖时间了?
Any chance you could give me the time?
今天都市侠博物馆开张 我可不想迟到
I don't want to be late for the opening of the Metro Man museum.
哦不 看来你要错过了
Oh no,looks like you're gonna miss it.
错过好几千年哪
By several thousand years.
噢 是吗?
Oh,am I?
大都会市民们 都市侠日快乐
Happy Metro Man day,Metro City.
今日天朗气清 市中心整洁有序 我们即将迎来一位绅士的光临
It's a beautiful day in beautiful downtown where we're here to honor a beautiful man.
都市侠
Metro Man.
他的心胸似海洋 但更宽广
His heart is an ocean that's inside a bigger ocean.
这些年 他的超级视力一直守卫着我们
For years he's been watching us with his super-vision.
超能力一直解救我们 博爱之心也关照我们
Saving us with his super strength,and caring for us with his super heart.
现在是我们回报他的时候了
Now it's our turn to give something back.
这里是Roxanne Ritchi为您 在都市侠博物馆落成典礼发回现场报道
This is Roxanne Ritchi reporting live,from the dedication of the Metro Man Museum.
刚才他们让你在广播里念的那一段
Wow,okay,the stuff they make you read on the air.
真难以置信 都疯了吧
That's unfreaking believable,it's crazy.
那是我自己写的 Hal
I wrote that piece myself,Hal.
其实我想说的是
What I was trying to say was,
在现代社会的新闻里还能出现艺术的闪光 真是难得啊
I can't believe that in our modern society they let like actual art get onto the news.
- 补得漂亮 Hal - 我们去喝杯咖啡什么的吧
-Nice save,Hal. - What are we,like lets just get a coffee or something.
今天可是都市侠的大日子
Come on,it's time to get in the Metro Man day spirit.
如果我是都市侠 决不会让大坏蛋绑架你那么多次
Well,if I were Metro Man Megamind wouldn't be kidnapping you all the time.
这是最重要的事
That's the first thing.
你真贴心
That's sweet of you.
我会像澳洲野狗看孩子一样看着你
And I'd be watching you,like a dingo watches a human baby.
- 呃 - 听起来有点怪
-Mmm. - Okay,that sounded,Okay that sounded a little weird.
确实有一点
A little bit,yeah.
你脸色怪怪的 我说什么好呢
And you're making a weird face,and that's making me feel weird.
不是爱啦 我们又没谈恋爱 我不是说我爱你
Not love,we're not in love.I'm not saying I love you.
好吧 我爱你 哎呀其实我也不是这个意思
Okay,I love you,whatever.I'm not saying like I'm in love with you.
我是说...Roxanne?Roxaroo?
I'm saying...Roxanne?Roxaroo?
好好上班
Get back to work.
政府花钱不是让你游手好闲的
The city doesn't pay you to loaf.
- 不许动! - 你们要干什么 伙计们?
-Freeze! - Whoa,what are you doing,guys?
是我!我是典狱长
It's ME!It's the Warden.
喂 开门
Hey,open up.
你们个蠢蛋 都被他玩了
Oh,you fools.He's tricked us.
你说得没错
You were right.
我一直都会是个大坏蛋
I'll always be a villain.
'坏到入骨' - George Thorogood
George Thorogood's 'Bad to the Bone'
坏到入骨 坏到入骨
Bad to the bone.Bad to the bone.
坏...坏...
B..B..B..Bad.B..B..B..Bad.
坏到入骨
Bad to the bone.
哎呀帅锅 要搭车吗?
Well hello good looking,need a lift?
当然要啦 大美鱼
Certainly do,you fantastic fish you.
快上车吧
Get in the car,you.
哟吼 我自由了
Whoo,I'm free.
你的手表棒极了 Minion
Thanks for sending me the watch,Minion.
那还用说 老板
You got it,boss.
冲啊
Punch it.
来吧 把双手举高
All right,put your hands in the air.
女士们绅士们 欢迎都市侠
Ladies and gentlemen,your Metro Man.
- 你们在等谁? - 都市侠
-Who's your Man? - Metro man.
你好 大都会!
Yeah,Metro City!
来吧 把手都给我 怎么样?
Give me some,come on give it now.Give it to me.What?
来击掌吧...非常好!
Give it to me...all right!
你 嗨 哈 哈 你
Yo,hey,ha,ha yo.
你好 大都会
Hey,Metro city.
你好
Hello,hey.
好了 大家都冷静一点吧
You know,I just want you to bring it down a bit.
小伙子们 小点声
Boys,a little lower.
谢谢
Thank you fellows.
我们现在说点实际的
Let's get real for a moment.
没错 就是那样
That's right,that's right ha,ha,that's right.
尽管有了自己的博物馆确实很酷
Although getting a whole museum is super cool.
很酷 但想知道我收过的最大荣誉吗?
Super cool,you want to know what the greatest honor you've given me is?
真的想知道?
Do you really want to know?
真的?
Really?
我告诉你们
I'll tell you.
你们给我的最大荣誉就是...
The greatest honor you've given me is...
...让我为你们服务
...letting me serve you.
帮助大都会里的市民
To help these people in Metro city.
每天临睡前
And at the end of every day.
嗯
Well.
我常常问自己
I often ask myself.
如果没有你们 我会是谁?
Who would I be,without you?
都市侠 我爱死你了!
I love you Metro Man!
我也爱你 市民朋友
And I love you,random citizen.
我跟你说 Minion 没什么能比得上自己的邪恶巢穴了
I tell you Minion,there's no place like evil lair.
我特意为您 让它保持潮湿阴冷
I kept it cold and damp,just for you,sir.
我看来怎么样 Minion?
How do I look,Minion?
- 看起来是个坏蛋吗? - 令人恐惧至极 先生
-Do I look bad? - Disgustingly horrifying,sir.
你拍马屁总能拍对地方
You always know what to say.
螺钉头们都想死你了 先生
All the brain-bots certainly missed you,sir.
想爸爸不?最能逞能的是那个小不点?
Did you miss your daddy?Whose the menacing little brains?
是你啊 啊!不许咬 不许咬哦
You are,yes you are.Uh,uh!No biting,no,no,no.
- 想要扳手吗?快去抢咯 - 看它们高兴的
-No,no,no.You want the wrench?Go get the wrench. - Oh,look at that.
现在 开始工作
Now,back to work.
她快醒了 快 准备好
She's awake,Quick,to work.
- Ritchi小姐 我们又见面了 - 把袋子洗干净会死吗?
-Miss Ritchi,we meet again. - Would it kill you to wash the bag?
随心所欲地叫吧 Ritchi小姐 天皇老子也听不见哦
You can scream all you wish,Miss Ritchi.I'm afraid no one can hear you.
她...她为什么不叫?
Wha..why isn't she screaming?
Ritchi小姐 如果你不介意的话
Miss Ritchi,if you don't mind.
就像这样...啊啊啊!
Like this...AHHHHH!
就是那样 可怜女士的叫法
That's,that's a poor ladies scream.
- 啊啊啊!!! - 你比我擅长多了
-AHHHHH!!! - It's a little better.
你们是在那个特傻的坏蛋网站上
Is there some kind of nerdy super villain website,
买的这堆磁暴线圈和发光转盘吗?
where you get Tesla coils,and blinky dials?
其实主要是在一家直销店...
Actually most of it comes from an outlet store in...
闭嘴
Don't answer that.
罗马尼亚那家
...Romania.
住口!闭嘴!别忘了她是个记者
Don't!Stop!She's using her nosey reporter skills,
她会利用你薄弱的毅力 获得我们全部机密
on your weak willed mind to find out all our secrets.
这点小把戏...哼 对我没用
Such tricks...won't work...on me.
- 能再说慢点吗 - 妖精
-Please talk slower -Temptress.
你有什么秘密?一眼就看到底了
What secrets?You're so predictable.
一眼就 看到底了?
Predictable,predictable?
哈 那你来试试这个?
Oh,you call THIS predictable?
鳄鱼而已嘛 没错吧
Your Alligators,yes.
来的路上我就想到了
I was thinking about it on the way over.
那这个呢?哇呜!
What's this?BOOM!
- 小心你的脸 - 陈词滥调
-In your face. - Clich?
不 等着看这个
No,look,watch.
幼稚
Juvenile.
- 启动! - 俗不俗啊你
-Shuck it all! - Tacky
- 哎呀这个太可怕了 - 早看见了
-Oh,so sorry. - Seen it.
- 这个呢? - 真俗
-What's this one do? - Garish.
好吧 蜘蛛是个新点子
Okay,the spiders new.
蜘蛛?
Spider?
啊 是的!
Ee,Uh,yes!
它叫 "织毒...蛛" 只要它轻轻咬你一口
The "spee..ider".Even the smallest bite from arachnis deathicus
你这辈子就瘫了...嗷!
Will instantly paralyze...OW!
把它扯掉!
Get it off!
放弃吧 大坏蛋 你的计划就没得逞过
Ow! - Give it up,Megamind.Your plans never work.
别浪费时间了 赶紧给你男朋友打电话吧?
Let's stop wasting time and call your boyfriend in tights,shall we?
很荣幸由我把博物馆授予 都市侠
It is with great pleasure that I present to Metro Man,this new museum.
请
If you please.
喂 我孩子看不见了
Uh,hey,my kid can't see.
- 超级大坏蛋 - 好极了 都市侠
-Megamind. - Oh,bravo Metro Man.
没错 我能和你们一起嘘哦
Yes,I can play along too.
早知道你会来砸场子的
Should have known you'd try to crash the party.
恐怕没砸场子这么简单
Oh,I intend to do more than crash it.
今天会让你和大都 "费" 永生难忘
This is the day you and Montrosity,shall not soon forget.
是大都会!
It's pronounced Metro City!
土了个豆 番了个茄 土豆 番茄
Oh,potato,tomato,potato,tomato.
我们都知道结局
We all know how this ends.
就是你再入监狱
With you behind bars.
哎呀 我穿着豹皮靴正发抖呢
Oh,I'm shaking in my custom baby seal-leather boots.
准备永别大都 "费" 吧
You will leave,Montrosity.
否则这就是你最后一次听见她了
Or this will be the last you ever hear of,
Roxanne Ritchi!
- 嗯? - Roxanne!
-Huh? - Roxanne!
- 别慌 Roxie 我马上就到 - 一点都不慌
-Don't panic Roxie,I'm on my way. - I'm not panicking.
想打败我 连我在哪都不知道 都市侠
In order to stop me,You need to find me first,Metro Man.
我们在废弃的天文台
We're at the abandoned observatory.
- 啊哈 - 不!不是!
-Ah ha. - NO!No we're not!
别听她瞎说 她疯了
Don't listen to her,she's crazy.
都市侠快到了 先生
Metro Man approaching,sir.
等一下
Hold on a second.
噢 天哪
Oh,good heavens.
没想到我们是在真的天文台吧 嗯?
You didn't think you were in the real observatory,did you?
准备启动死亡射线 Minion
Ready the death ray,Minion.
死亡射线 准备待发
Death ray,readying.
看这边 我的老朋友
Over here,old friend.
友情提醒下
In case you haven't noticed,
你中了我的计了
You've fallen right into my trap.
正义永远不会被打败 这是理想 是信仰
You can't trap justice.It's an idea,a belief.
就算最虔诚的信仰 也被时间侵蚀
Even the most heartfelt belief,can be corroded over time.
正义是不锈钢
Justice is a noncorrosive metal.
是金属就会被 "球" 恨这热融化的
But metals can be melted by the heat of 're-vange'.
是仇恨 而且最好冷藏保存
It's 'revenge' and it's best served cold.
有邪恶微波炉 想加热太容易了
But it can be easily reheated,in the microwave of evil.
我猜它快到保修期了吧
Well I think your warranty is about to expire.
我就不能延长保修吗?
Maybe I got an extended warranty?
如果你不正确使用产品 保修是无效的
Warranties are invalid if you don't use the product for its intended purpose.
哎乖乖乖 你们漂亮极了 我可以回家了吧?
Oh,girls,girls,you're both pretty.Can I go home now?
当然 不过前提是都市侠 可以承受无敌聚焦...太阳光!
Of course,that is if Metro Man,can withstand the full concentrated power of the...SUN!
开火!
FIRE!
Minion 开火...
Minion,fire...
先生 还在预热
Uh,it's still warming up,sir.
- 你说什么? - 还是预热 先生
-Come again? - Warming up,sir.
预热?太阳也要预热?
Warming up?The sun is warming up?
就一小会
One...sssecond...more.
马上...
aaannnd....jussst.
再来一点 上来了快了
Tippy,tappy tippy tap,tap,tip top more.
- 天啊 - 马上就好 再等
-Honestly. - And we are ready,in just.
天!跟你说过一切都准备好啊
Oh!I told you to have things ready.
跟你说过多少遍了
I told you countless times.
你干吗老是怨我?
Why do you always blame me?
我蜘蛛毒发了
My spider bite is acting.
承认吧 你又失败了
Your plan is failing,just admit it.
是啊 希望下次成功
Yeah,good luck with that one.
你到底是哪一边的?
Whose side are you on?
输的一边
The losing side.
- 谢谢 - 能给我的被绑架常旅客卡盖章吗?
-Thank you. - Uh,could someone stamp my frequent kidnapping card?
你该清楚 那个促销早就不办了
You of all people,know we discontinued that promotion.
- 再见了 - 下周老时间?
-Chow,chow all. - Same time next week?
他刚才说什么?
What did he just say?
该死的金块?
Crab nuggets?
天啊 我飞不出去
Good lord,I'm trapped.
他又玩什么把戏?
What kind of trickery is this?
你个狂人 你的诡计得逞了
You mad genius.Your dark gift has finally paid off.
成 成功了?
It,it has?
这个圆屋顶包着铜
This dome is obviously lined with copper.
- 没错 然后? - 先生!
-Yeah,so? - Sir!
铜耗尽了我的能量
Copper drains my powers.
你的弱点是铜?
Your weakness is copper?
开玩笑呢吧你?
You're kidding,right?
我觉得他这次死定了
I don't think even he could survive that.
欢迎来到 大都会犯罪天才监狱
超级大坏蛋
扫描模式
先别抱这么大的希望
Well,lets not get our hopes up just yet.
- 看! - 都市侠
-Look! - Metro Man.
都市侠...
Metro Man...
都市侠!啊~!
Metro Man!AHHH!
哦 天哪!哦 我的天哪 哦!
Oh god!Oh my god,oh!
呃~~~
Ewwww.
您成功了 主人
You did it,sir.
我成功了?
I did it?
他成功了
He did it.
我成功了
I did it.
他成功了
He did it.
- 您成功了 主人 - 我成功了
-You did it,sir. - I did it!
- 您成功了 - 我成功了!
-You did it. - I did it!
大都会是我的了!
Montrocity is mine!
您成功了 主人 您成功了 主人 是您成功了
You did it sir,you did it,sir.Yes you did.
好了 唱吧
All right people,hit it.
放音乐!
Hit it!
'通往地狱的公路' - AC/DC
AC/DC's HIGHWAY TO HELL
简单生活 自由的爱
Living easy, loving free
拿上季票 踏上单程旅行
Season ticket on a one-way ride
无需理由 无需节奏
Don't need reason,don't need rhyme
- 不为所图 只因我愿意 - 放下枪
- Ain't got nothing I'd rather do. - Drop 'em.
继续前行 派对时间 朋友齐聚在前方
Going down,party time My friends are gonna be there too,
我在通往(地狱的)公路上...
I'm on the Highway to (hell)...
公路上... 啦~...
Highway... La,la,la,la,la...
公路上... 啊~...
Highway... Ahh,ahh,ahh...
首先 真是意外啊
First off,what a turnout.
很疯狂 对吧?
How wild is this,huh?
我所做的只是消灭了全宇宙最强的人
All I did was eliminate the most powerful man in the universe.
还有什么疑问吗?
Are there any questions?
问吧 后面那位
Come on..yes?You in the back.
我肯定大家都想知道 你会怎么处置我们
I'm sure we'd all like to know what you plan to do with us.
和这座城市
And the city.
很好 真高兴你能这么问
Good,I'm glad you asked that one.
想想你们心中最恐怖邪恶的事情
Imagine,the most horrible,terrifying evil thing you could possibly think of.
然后再变本加厉个...六倍!
And multiply it by...SIX!
但在这此间我希望 你们继续无聊乏味的
In the mean time I want you to carry on,with the dreary normal things you,
日常生活
Normal people do.
好好享受吧
Let's just have fun with this,come on.
我会再回复你们的
And I will get back to you.
现在重重地摔门
Now slam the door,really hard.
他们...还是能看到你
They can...they can still see you.
- 现在呢? - 是的 你还在啊
Now?Yeah,you're still there.
我们闪吧
Oh,let's get going.
邪恶大王 驾到了
There he is,Mr.Evil Overlord.
啊 Minion
Ahh,Minion.
你有想过今天的到来吗?
Did you think this day would ever come?
从没 一点都没想到 主人 从没 过个几万年也没可能...
No way,not at all,sir.Never,never in a million,I mean...
我想过
Yes,I did.
看看这精美的吊顶
Look at the intricate moon links.
我看着呢 看着呢
I'm looking,I'm looking.
这是什么?
And what's this?
看上去像基地里的大监视器
Looks like one of the giant monitors,in the lair.
但好像只有一个画面
But it seems to only carry one station.
哦 主人 那个叫窗户
Oh,that sir is called a window.
- 窗户... - 所有孩子都通过它向外看
-Window... - All the kids are looking through them.
哦 我以前从没看到过
Oooo,I've never had a view before.
大都会 Minion 它是我的了
Montrosity Minion,it's all mine.
如果我的父母能看到我
If my parents could see me now.
主人 我肯定他们会在恶棍天堂里微笑的
Sir,I'm sure they're smiling down from evil heaven.
现在好好超人已经不能挡路了
Well now that Mr.Goody-two-shoes is out of the way.
我可以拥有一切我想要的了!
I can have,everything I want!
而且没人能阻止我了
And there's no one to stop me.
'疯狂列车' - Ozzy Osbourne
Ozzy Osbourne's 'CRAZY TRAIN'
全体上车!哈 哈 哈~...
All aboard!Ha,ha,haaaa...
精神创伤在愈合 使我更疯狂
Mental wounds healing,Driving me insane.
我正在发疯 在这疯狂的列车上
I'm going off the rails,on a crazy train.
'自然而然 再次孤独' - Gilbert Osullivan
Gilbert Osullivan's 'Alone Again Naturally'
我们还是回家吧 就如同我行我素
We may as well go home,as I did on my own.
自然而然 再次孤独
Alone again,naturally.
想起就在昨日
To think that only yesterday.
我还欢喜雀跃
I was cheerful bright and gay.
期待着 任谁都不会象我这样 做我(所担当)的角色...
Looking forward to,well who wouldn't do,the role I was about( to play)...
我知道 我知道 老是饥渴 永不满足
I know,I know.Always thirsty,never satisfied.
我能理解 小小漂亮鸟
I understand you,little well dressed bird.
无目标 寂寞 真是空虚啊 你的空虚又是啥?
Purposeless,emptiness,it's a vacuum isn't it.What's your vacuum like?
正在发疯 在这疯狂的列车上 先生
Going off the rails,on a crazy train,sir.
嘿 嘿 嘿!现在不行 Minion
Hey,hey,hey!Not now,Minion.
我和这死鱼眼的塑料玩具 正在进行关于自我存在的激辩
I'm in a heated existential discussion with this dead-eyed plastic desk toy.
我...有什么不对吗 主人?
I...is something wrong,sir?
仔细想想
Just think about it.
我们拥有了一切
We have it all.
但又如此空虚
But we have nothing.
现在得到太过于容易
It's just to easy now.
抱歉 我听蒙了 主人
I'm sorry,you've lost me,sir.
- 我们是成功了 对吗? - 是您成功了 主人
-I mean,we did it,right? - Well,you did it,sir.
是的 你说得很清楚了
Yes you've made that perfectly clear.
- 那为什么我感觉这么 没气力? - 呃?
-Then why do I feel so,Mel-on-cholly? - Huh?
不高兴
Unhappy.
哦 那个 明儿我们去绑架Roxanne Ritchi如何?
Oh,uh well,uh.What if tomorrow,we could go kidnap Roxanne Ritchi.
那一直对您都很给力
That always seems to lift your spirits.
好主意 Minion 但没有他 有啥意义呢?
Good idea,Minion.But without him,what's the point?
- 什么他 主人? - 没什么
-Him,sir? - Nothing.
好吧 那么 那就...
Okay,um,all right well just uh,that's uh,
当是备用选项吧
something to consider and um,
我想我还是休息一下吧
well,I think I'll just power down for a while then.
我们一直被他守护着
He was always there for us.
依靠他
Dependable.
也许我们太习以为常了
Perhaps we took him for granted.
直到失去时才懂得去珍惜
Maybe we never really know how good we have it,until it's gone.
我们想念你 都市侠
We miss you,Metro Man.
我也想你了
I,miss you.
我对超级大坏蛋只有一个问题
And I have just one question for,Megamind.
现在你高兴了?
Are you happy now?
这是Roxanne Ritchi 在这座无超人的城市为您报道
This is Roxanne Ritchi reporting from a city without a hero.
接下来 你想当奴隶大军吗?你们该知道的
Coming up next.Are you ready to be a slave army?What you need to know.
完美收尾 当是孩子的圣诞礼物
Aaannd wrap that up and give it to a child on Christmas.
- 因为我们完工了 - 好了 明天见 Hal
-'Cause we're done. - Okay,see you tomorrow,Hal.
等等 Roxie 我家正要办个派对
Wait,Roxie.I'm having a party at my house.
就算是放松一下什么的 你应该来玩
Coming off the hook,or whatever.You should come over.
我找了个DJ 租了个气垫屋 还有一堆酒 会很狂欢的
I got a DJ rented a bouncy house.Made a gallon of dip.It's gonna be sick.
我不知道 Hal 我不太想去人多的地方
Oh,I don't know,Hal.I don't really fell like being around a bunch of people.
不 不 不 那更好 因为只有你和我
No,no,no.That's the best part,it'll be like just you and me.
哇哦 那很吸引人啊
Wow,that uh,that's certainly very tempting.
- 但是... - 我还请了个婚礼摄影师
-But, - I did hire a wedding photographer.
只是以防我们会做什么疯事
That's just in case,we were like something crazy happened.
像是你想拍张照片 也许我们应该拍一张当是
And you'd want a picture of it.Like maybe we should have this for like ever,
永久的纪念
like a memory,you know.
嗯 我还是不去了
Um,I'm gonna pass.
还有事要做呢 好了 再见
I have some work here I need to do.Okay,bye.
周四如何?周四可以考虑?
So Thursday?Soft,Thursday?
- 晚安 Hal - 那就是有机会了 周四哦
-Goodnight,Hal. - It's a soft yes,on Thursday.
我是怎么搞的?
What's,wrong with me?
租了间气垫屋?女孩又不喜欢那个 她们喜欢小丑嘛
Rented a bouncy house?Chick's don't like bouncy houses,they like clown's.
噢!哦~
OW!Ohhh!
该死的笨车!弄断我的手指!
Stupid van!Broke my finger!
我犯了个大错误
I've made a horrible mistake.
我不是有意要灭你的
I didn't mean to destroy you.
我是说我有意要灭你
I mean,I meant to destroy you.
但没想过会成功
I didn't think it would really work.
我们接下来要怎么做?没有你 恶人横行街头
What are we suppose to do?Without you,evil is running rampant through the streets.
我厌倦了横行街头
I am so tired of running rampant through the streets.
没有英雄阻止 作恶又有何意思?
What's the point of being bad when there's no good to try and stop you?
得有人来阻止超级大坏蛋
Someone has to stop,Megamind.
嘿 我们要关门了
Hey,we're closing soon.
哦 你吓死我了
Oh,you scared me.
- Barry吧? - Bernard
-Barry,right? - Bernard.
Bernard 我只是...在自言自语
Bernard,I was just well I was talking to myself.
你可能觉得我有点犯傻了
You may think I'm a little bit nuts.
我可没被允许乱猜测
I'm not allowed to self guess directly.
谢谢 我只是...
Thank you,I just...
Bernard 我过会就走
Bernard,I'll just be another minute.
- 好的 - 谢谢
-Okay. - Thanks.
我还是很多邪恶的计划没启用呢
I had so many evil plans in the works.
文盲射线
The illiteracy beam.
台风奶酪
Typhoon cheese.
机器山羊
Robo sheep.
那要是打起来一定空前绝后
Battles we will now,never have.
我们都没机会好好道个别
You know we never had the chance to say goodbye.
所以现在我们要好好叙叙
So,it's good that we have this time now.
趁着我还没炸飞这里之前
You know,before I destroy the place.
不是针对你的 只是这里给了我很多悲惨的回忆
Nothing personal,it just brings back to many painful memories.
有人吗?
Hello,hello?
Roxanne!
这装扮真没品
That's a pretty tasteless costume.
- 装扮? - 超级大坏蛋的头没大得这么恶心
-Costume? - Megamind's head is not that grossly exaggerated.
哦 你还做了把劣质的仿冒脱水枪 真是...
Oh you even made a cheap replica of his dehydration gun.How...
你好 有人在那吗?
Hello,is someone there?
你好 谁在那?
Hello,who's there?
哇哦!嘿嘿
Whoa!Hey,hey.Whew.
是你啊 Bernard
It's just you,Bernard.
是的 就是我 Bernard
Oh,yes it's just me.Bernard.
谢谢你能让我多呆会
Well thank you for letting me stay.
要换是我 就不会多呆个2分30秒
Look I wouldn't stay for more than two minutes and thirty seven seconds if I were you.
这里的墙和天花板都要换掉
We're having the walls and ceiling removed.
哇哦 听起来要大改造啊
Wow,that sounds like.Quite the renovation.
我跟你一起下去吧
I guess I'll.Guess I'll ride down with you then.
我一直以为他能在最后一秒逃出生天
I kept thinking he was going to do one of his last minute escapes.
是啊 他很在行的说
Yeah,he was really good at those.
哦 要是世界有重启按钮该有多好啊
Oh,if only the world had a reset button.
我也想要重启按钮啊
I've looked into the reset button.
但做不到那尺寸啊
The size is impossible.
哦 Bernard 你也会...感慨啊 你还好吗?
Oh,Bernard,I didn't know you had...feelings.Are you okay?
都市侠已经去世了 现在没人能对抗超级大坏蛋了
Metro Man is gone.And now there's no one left to challenge Megamind.
拜托 Bernard
Oh,come on,Bernard.
有邪恶的地方 就会诞生正义
As long as there's evil good will rise up against it.
哦 我希望啊
Ohhh,I wish.
我坚信一定有人会觉醒来对抗超级大坏蛋
I believe someone is going to stand up to Megamind.
- 你真这么想? - 是的
-You really think so? - Yeah.
就像老话说的 英雄不是天生的 而是被塑造的
I mean,it's like they say.Heroes aren't born,they're made.
英雄是被塑造的 对了!
Heroes can be made.That's it!
- 我们要做的就是找到对的成分 - 是啊
-All you need are the right ingredients. - Yeah.
- 勇敢 - 是的
-Bravery. - Yes.
- 力量 - 当然
-Strength. - Of course.
- 决心 - 必要
-Determination. - Imperative.
还有一点DNA
And a smidgen of DNA.
- 有了这些 任何人都能成英雄 - 对头
-With that,anyone can be a hero. - Yeah!
哦 哦 哦 哦!
Oh,ho,ho,ho!
我想我们该跑了
I think we should run.
再见
Bye.
现在该忘记过去
Time to put the past behind us.
展望未来了...哈!
Only the future...AHH!
哦 我离得太近 真是吓到我了
Oh,I'm to close.I'm genuinely scared right now.
哦 我可不希望有人看到
Oh,I hope no ones seeing this.
造英雄?等等 您为什么要这么做?
Create a hero?Wait,wait,what?Why would you do that?
这样我才有对手啊
So I have someone to fight.
Minion 我是个没有对手的恶棍
Minion,I'm a villain without a hero.
缺少阳的阴
A ying,with no yang.
没有牛斗的斗牛士
A bull fighter with no bull to fight.
换句话说 我没了目标
In other words,I have no purpose.
现在问我如何造英雄
Now,ask me how I'm going to do it.
快问吧
Go on,ask.
您要如何造英雄?
How are you doing to do it?
我要找个人 现在还不知道是谁
I'm going to give someone,I don't know who yet.
给他都市侠的超能力 还要把那人训练成大都市的新英雄
Metro Man's powers.I'm going to train that someone to become Montrocity's new hero.
这里呢 跟着点
Over here,follow.
最后我将和他对打 来一场正义与邪恶的大战
And then,finally I'm going to fight that hero.In an epic battle of good and evil.
我们要将一切恢复正常
We could put everything back the way it was.
到时世界就变得完美
When the world was perfect.
和美好 听好了 Minion
And rosy.Behold,Minion.
都市侠的斗篷
Metro Man's cape.
仔细看清楚
Look closely.
你看到了什么?
Tell me what you see?
头屑?
Dandruff?
是的 是他的DNA
Yes,it's his DNA.
有了这个 我们能提取都市侠的超能力
From this,we'll extract the source of Metro Man's awesome power.
主人 我觉得这是坏主意
Sir,I think this is a bad idea.
是的 对一个好人来说 这是个非常坏的点子
Yes,It's a very wickedly bad idea.For the greater good of man.
但我的意思那是个很糟糕的主意
But I'm saying this is a kind of bad,bad.
好吧 因为您出发点是坏的 所以觉得是个好主意
Okay,you might think it's good in your bad perception.
但往好的方向想 这真的是个坏主意
But from a good perception,it is just plain bad.
哦 你又不知道 对坏蛋来说什么是好主意
Oh,you don't know what's good for bad.
现在我们只有一次机会
Now we have just one shot at this.
得找到一个合适的人选
We must find a suitable subject.
那人会来对抗我 会舍己为人
Someone who will do harm to mine.Who puts the welfare of others above their own.
这是啥声音?
What on earth is that?
好像是从那里传出来的 主人
Seems to be emanating from there,sir.
- 哦好 - 呃 是你好
-O-llo, - Uh,it's hello.
你好 这样吗?
Hello,like that?
- Bernard 是我Roxanne - 是Roxanne
-Bernard,it's Roxanne. - It's Roxanne.
我想谢谢你那天激发了我
I just want to thank you for inspiring me the other day.
- 哦 你也激发了我 - 很好!
-Oh,You've inspired me too. - Great!
是时候翻身去对抗超级大坏蛋了 让他们见识下我们的厉害
It's time we stood up to Megamind and show him he can't push us around.
哦 哦 真的吗?她真可爱
Oh,oh really.She's so cute.
- 我已经掌握他的行踪了 - 呃
-I'm already hot on his trail. - Uh,huh.
你是怎么知道的?
And what gives you that idea?
- 呃 主人 - 我刚找到了他的秘密基地
-Uh,sir. - I just found his secret hideout.
她是怎么找到的?
How did she find my hideout?
呃 你是怎么找到的?
Uh,how did you find his hideout?
因为只有这座建筑有t望台
This is the only building in Metro City with a big observatory on the roof.
好吧 那她也找不到秘密入口
Okay,there's no way she'll find the secret entrance.
哦!这里有个门垫 写着"秘密入口"
Oh!There's a doormat here that say's 'Secret Entrance'.
- Minion! - 人家老是忘记嘛
-Minion! - I kept forgetting where it was.
她会发现我们所有的秘密的
She'll discover all our secrets.
- 哦 不好! - 你真是科学造出的白痴
-Ohh,oh no! - You dim-witted creation of science.
- 什么? - 哦 不是说你Roxanne
-What? - Oh,not you Roxanne.
不是 我是在对我的妈妈们喊
No,I was just yelling at my mothers,urn.
不要乱动 我这就来
Don't do anything,I'll be right there.
Roxanne?
哦 不 又来了
Oh no,not again.
Roxanne．
Roxanne.
哦 我真高兴你来了
-Whoa! - Oh,I'm glad you're here.
等等 你怎么来得这么快?
Wait,how did you get here so fast?
那个 我 呃 你打给我时 我正在竞走
Well,I uh.I happened to be speed walking nearby when you called.
- 穿着西装? - 呃
-In a suit? - Uh huh.
这是"竞走正式装"
It's called,'Formal Speed walking'.
但这不重要啦
But that's not important.
我还是来带路吧
I better take the lead.
这里写着是出口
This way looks exciting.
不 那是出口
No,it says,exit.
呃 是"输出入口"的简称 对吧?
Uh,which is the abbreviation for 'Exciting',right?
这里是主控室
It's the mother load.
- 啊 - 哇哦
-Ahh. - Wow.
- 哇哦 - 看看这东西
-Wow. - Just look at this thing.
我真的需要你来帮我解读一下
You know,I really could use your help in deciphering all this.
- 真的吗? - 你对超级大坏蛋很有研究 对吧?
-Really? - You're an expert in all things Megamind,right?
- 是的 - 团结就能找到并阻止他的邪恶计划
-Yes,right. - Together we could figure out his plan for the city and stop it.
你同意吗?
Are you in?
- 哦 乐意之至! - 这才对嘛
-Oh,what fun! - That's what I want to hear.
Minion 接暗号 去把脑虫放出来
Minion,Code-Send in the brain bots.
所谓的暗号是指...
You know the whole point of a code is...
哦 接暗号去做 Minion
Oh code-just do it,Minion.
啊 是我啊 笨蛋!
Ahh,it's me you fools!
Bernard!
是爹地啦
It's daddy.
超级大坏蛋!
Megamind!
你把Bernard怎么了?
What have you done with,Bernard?
哦 Bernard?哦 是的 我要对那人施以酷刑
Oh Bernard?Oh yes,I'm doing horrible things to that man.
我不想细说 但有激光 长钉
I don't want to get into it but,Lasers,spikes.
哦 不要 不要用激光和长钉!
Oh,please no,not the lasers and the spikes!
你还不清楚吗
You know the drill.
哦 不 不要用钻子
Oh no,not the drill.
- 放他走 - 不然如何?
-Let him go. - Or what?
不然我就用你来试这怪枪
Or I'm going to find out what this weird looking gun does.
不要!别开枪
No don't!Don't shoot that gun.
我去带他出来
I'll just go get him.
放开我 恶魔!
Unhand me you fiend!
太强大了
It,its strength's to much.
哥可是练过的
Oh,I work out.
那你就要惨了 你这么苗条 而我是天生神力
Argh,it's really paying off.You're so fit,and strangely charismatic.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
我尽力了 但他太厉害了
I've did my best.But he's to fantastic.
来 让我扛这大枪吧
Here,let me carry that heavy gun for you.
我能行
I got this covered.
放手 那是我的!
Let go,it's mine!
Bernard 快跑!
Bernard,run!
还给我
Give it to me.
哦 不!
Oh no!
Roxanne．
Roxanne.
哦!
Ow!
那是啥东东啊?
Who on earth is that?
Roxanne!
Bernard 你猜对了 那门就是出口
Bernard,you were right about that door being exciting.
这边走
This way.
你干嘛?
-Aha! - What are you doing?
这能阻止它们 给!
This will stop them,here!
好像有点过火了吧
Seems a bit extreme,doesn't it.
快扔啊
Just throw it.
爹地很抱歉
Daddy's,sorry.
- 哇哦 真是太刺激了 - 是啊
-Wow,that was real exciting. - Yeah.
- 你表现得很勇敢 - 我知道
-You were very strong in there. - I know.
除了都市侠 我还没见谁能这样对抗他
I've never seen anyone but Metro Man stand up to him like that.
出什么事了?
What's going on?
Hal 怎么了?
Hal,what happened?
好像一只蜜蜂钻进我鼻子了
I think a bee flew up my nose.
我正想正面突击去救你
I was just about to make my frontal assault to rescue you,
但好像有5个忍者挡住了我
but like fifty ninjas started to attack me.
所以我得先制服他们 也成功了
So I had to beat them all up,and I did...
- 他们被打得抱头痛哭 - 哇哦
-and they were all like crying,and stuff. - Wow.
他很英勇 对吧
Brave one,isn't he.
你是哪位?
Who are you?
这是Bernard
Oh thi...,this is Bernard.
- 他是我的搭档 - 搭档?
-He's my partner. - Partner?
是...是的 搭档
Yes,yes partner.
去你的搭档 我才是她的搭档
Well look partner,I'm her partner.
她惊魂未定 胡说八道呢
She doesn't know what she's saying.She's been through a traumatic experience.
我还是送他回家吧 谢谢了 Bernard
I'd better take him home.Thanks again,Bernard.
明天打给你 搭档
I'll call you tomorrow,partner.
好的
Yeah,okay.
很荣幸
I'd like that.
所有人都不正常 连你都抱他不抱我
That was weird for everybody.'Cause you accidentally,hugged him instead of me.
长官!
Sir!
SIR!
你找出它的身份了吗?
Code-Did you find out who it was?
什么?噢
Huh?Oh,oh.
车子呢
Code-get the car.
马上到 长官
Code-right away,sir.
- 再见 - 明天见 Hal
-Bye. - See you tomorrow,Hal.
我门不锁了 随时等你来检查
I'll leave the door unlocked in case you want to check on me later.
这人是谁?他被灌入超人的力量
Who is this man,we've infused with godlike power?
噢 哇
Ow,ow,whoa ho.
报告长官 他叫Hal Stewart 28岁
Well sir,his name's Hal Stewart.He's twenty eight years old.
无犯罪记录
No criminal record.
根本没任何记录
Actually,no records at all.
看来这人一事无成
Apparently,this man hasn't accomplished anything.
别妄下定论 Minion
Not yet,Minion.Not...
别
...Yet.
还有更好的事发生吗?
Could this day get anymore,funtastic?
我马上消除他的力量
So I will just go ahead and defuse him,
显然这是个错误
since this is clearly a mistake.
不 Minion 更强大的力量就要出现了
No,Minion.Something much more powerful at work.
这不是错误
This is no mistake.
这是命运
It's destiny.
Hal Stewart 迎接你的命运吧
Hal Stewart,prepare for your destiny.
Hal?Hal Stewart?
我说得对吗?
Am I saying it right?
- Stewart - 啊
-Stewart. - Aaah.
打劫吗?大堂对面的女人比我有钱
Is this a robbery?'Cause the lady across the hall has way better stuff than me.
看 这是Hal Stewart
Oh,look.It's Hal Stewart.
快 喷雾
Quick,the spray.
- 用完了 - 那就用失忆棒
-Oops,all out. - Well use the forget-me-stick.
对!
Oh,right!
看看他吧
Just look at him.
他看上去不像个英雄
Well,he doesn't look quite the hero type to me.
你个讨厌鬼 Minion
Oh,you're such a pill,Minion.
力量不能对外表要求太高
The power couldn't ask for a finer claim.
我闻到英雄的味道
I smell hero.
有东西烧起来的味道
I smell something burning.
一定是起反应了!
I think it's working!
就位 就位...
Places,places,places,places...
你可以易容吗?
You have your disguise?
什么?
What?
你看上去酷毙了
Ah,you look fantastic.
起来吧 我神圣的作品
Rise,my glorious creation.
起来 到爸爸这儿来
Rise,and come to Papa.
发生什么事?
What's going on?
- 放轻松 我的孩子 - 你是谁?
-Easy my child. - Who are you?
我把你送到这个世界 为了教导你正义
I sent you to this planet to teach you about justice.
荣誉 和高尚
Honor,and nobility.
我是你的老爸
I am your father.
你就像 我的太空老爸?
So you're like,my space Dad?
是 我就像你的太空老爸
Yeah,I'm like your space Dad.
你又是什么?
And you are,what?
我是你的太空 后妈
I'm your space,Step-Mom.
最近好好修饰过了
I,I had some work done recently.
这是在做梦吗?
Is this some kind of dream?
梦已经实现了
This is a dream come true.
你被赐予不可估量的强大力量
You've been blethed with unfathomamble power.
什么样的力量?
What kind of power?
深不可测的
Unfathamomble.
就是没法找到的
It's un,without Fathom.
- 哇 - 我们来指引你
-Whoa -Yeah,we've come to guide you.
成为大都费的新英雄
On your path to be Montrosity's new hero.
打败超级大坏蛋
And battle the super genius,of Megamind.
我知道这很难理解
I know this is a lot to take in.
你可能要花几个月练习控制力...
It may take months for you to come to grips..
没门儿
No frickin' way.
我还没说完呢
I wasn't finished.
哇!我要变成英雄了
Wahoo!I'm going to be a hero.
我要变成英雄了
I'm going to be a hero.
Minion 他太完美了
Thee Minion,he's perfect.
开始!
Aaannd,action!
- 帮我一把 - 我没事
Someone help me. - I'm okay.
阳光明媚的天空
Sun is shinning in the sky
哦~ 哦!
Ohhh,oh!
眼前没有一丝云彩
There ain't a cloud in sight
杀 杀 杀
Zap,zap,zap.
哈 哈~!
Ha,haaa!
我的恶魔之火已经点燃 现在你对我说些好听的
The flames of my evil burn bright.Now you thay thomething cool back at me.
根本就不痛 感觉不到
Look,it doesn't even hurt.Don't even feel it.
不 不 慢点 然后停下
No,no,no.Slow it down,and stop.
我说了慢点
I said slow down.
当心
Watch out.
他没救了 彻底没救了!
He's hopeless.HOPELESS!
- 可能要改变方法? - 你这么想?
-Maybe we should change tactics? - You think so?
男生嘛 都喜欢打游戏
Oh,you know how boys are.They love video games.
我能同时扔起很多部分
I can throw a few parts together.
等不及了 LoL 笑脸
Can't...wait.LoL, smiley face.
长官 等不急干吗?
Can't wait for what,sir?
那件事太搞笑了
Oh,that was such a funny story.
当然 描述得也很棒
And brilliantly told,by the way.
好吧 轮到你讲了
Okay,now you tell one.
Bernard 我以前从没发现你这么有趣
Bernard,I never knew you were so funny.
而且也没听你大笑过
And,I never heard you laugh before.
是呀 有阵子没笑了
Yeah,it's been a while.
感觉很好
Feels pretty good.
'蓝先生的天空' - Jeff Lynne
Jeff Lynne's 'Mr Blue Sky'
蓝先生 你做得对
Mr.Blue,you did it right.
接下来 出口
And,exit.
他的手正搭在你的肩上
Now his hand is on your shoulder
别介意
Never mind
我会记住你这个
I'll remember you this,
我会记住你这个习惯
I'll remember you this way.
你不经常出来吧?
You don't get out much,do you?
好玩!
Fun!
小时候经常和我妈来这儿
I used to come here with my mother when I was a kid.
那是我最喜欢的事之一
It was one of my favorite things to do.
现在呢
Now look at it.
变垃圾场了
It's a dump.
嗨 蓝先生 跟你在一起 我们很快乐
Hey Mr.Blue,we're so please to be with you.
长官 我们为什么要打扫城市?
Why are we cleaning up the City,sir?
总不想在垃圾堆里战斗吧?
Um,well we don't want to battle our new hero in a dump,now...do we?
一切都回来了
They're all back.
怎么会的?
But how,why?
可能超级大坏蛋不是想象中那么坏
Maybe Megamind isn't so bad after all.
就是这样 放松点 我的小肥鸽
That's it.Be free,my beautiful dove.
哇~
Wa haoooo
都市侠和我从没在一起过
Okay,okay,Metro Man and I,were never a couple.
但我觉得你们俩是...
But I thought you two were...
大家都这么想 只是 他不是我喜欢的类型
I know,everybody did.It's just,well he was never really my type.
真的?
Really?
现在说说你吧
Okay,now you tell me something.
没跟别人说过的秘密
Something you've never told anyone.
在鞋...学校
Well,in shh-school.
同学都不喜欢我
None of the other kids really liked me.
所有事都是最后一个轮到我
I was always last one picked for everything.
真可惜我们不是一个学校
Hmm,it's to bad that we didn't go to the same school.
Hal 你该试试这个了
Hal,I think you're ready for this.
给我儿子吗?
Do I have a son?
不 Hal 你真幽默
No,Hal,you make me laugh.
有弹性的 这是给你的
It stretches,it's for you.
"T"是什么意思?
Hey,what's the 'T' stand for?
Titan (巨人)
Titan.
紧身?什么意思?
Tighten?What's that suppose to mean?
这是我唯一注册过的商标
It was the only name I could trademark.
噢
Oh.
有对你来说非常特殊的人吗 Hal?
Do you have someone special in your life,Hal?
不 还没有 但是
No not yet,but.
我正对一个漂亮女人目不转睛
There's this really,really good looking one I've got my eye on,currently.
那很好 爱情能带来灵感
That's very good.Romance is very inspiring.
- 我懂了 - 你要做的就是 留住她
-That's what I hear. - All you have to do,is save her.
她就会属于你
And she'll be yours.
- 谁要吃油条? - 我要!
-Who want's Churro's? - I do!
谢谢你去太空买 妈妈
Thanks spaced out,momma.
数到三 拔出油条
On the count of three,unsheathe your Churro.
1 2 3 为了Titan!
One,two,three!To Titan.
明天你就要和超级大坏蛋一决高下
Tomorrow,you will fight Megamind.
整个城市会记住你的名字
And the city will know your name.
城市公园恢复原有风貌
The City's parks' restored to their original glory.
街道变得很安全
The street's,the safest they've been.
银行重新开业
The banks reopened.
超级大坏蛋怎么了?
Has something happened to Megamind?
是否有人驯服了这只野兽?
Has someone tamed this monster?
我是Roxanne Ritchi 带着谨慎的乐观和欣慰的疑惑报道
This is Roxanne Ritchi cautiously optimistic,and pleasantly confused.
看来今晚你心情不错 长官
Well you seem in a very good mood tonight,sir.
啊?噢 是的 这要花多久?
Huh?Oh yes,how long is this going to take?
就一点小改动 我会做适合你的最恐怖的斗篷
Just a few alterations,sir.And I will be done with your most terrifying cape yet.
我称它为 黑蟒...蛇
I'm calling it,The Black Mambaaaaaaa...aaaa...aaa.
黑蛇 太好了 天呢 我要走了 快迟到了
Black Mamba,perfect.Ooo,gosh I am running late.I have to go.
什么 你要去哪里 长官?
What,where,where are you going,sir?
明早就要和Titan开战了
We have our debut battle with Titan tomorrow morning.
还没测试你的战袍呢
We haven't even tested your big battle suit yet.
具体细节交给你了 Minion
You attend to the details,Minion.
我有急事
I have to,run a quick errand.
你没什么好忙的
You don't run errands.
发生什么了?
What's going on here?
- 什么? - 慢着
-What? - Oh,wait a minute.
你是不是为了他喷了 Jean-Paul Gaultier香水 ?
Are you wearing Jean-Paul Gaultier's,For Him?
这只是平时的装扮
It's just my natural musk.
车钥匙在哪儿?
Now,where are the car keys?
啊
Ahhh.
啊 啊 是Ritchi小姐 不是吗?
Uh,uh,uh,uh.This is about Ms.Ritchi,isn't it.
你和她在约会
Your going on a date with her.
少来了 我的朋友
No my main man,get out of town.
你爱上她就糟糕了
Oh this is bad,this is bad.You've fallen in love with her.
别忘了你的身份 Minion
You are forgetting your place,Minion.
给我钥匙
Now give me the keys.
万一Roxanne发现你的真面目呢?
What happens when Roxanne finds out who you really are?
她不会知道的
She will never find out.
这就是该撒谎的时候
That's the point of lying.
啊!
Ahhh!
老实说 如果我没猜错 今天是你变坏的第一天
Honestly,If I didn't know any better I'd think this was your first day of being evil.
不!
NO!
太过分了
This has gone far enough.
还真成熟啊
Oh,that was really grown up.
长官 听我说 这是为你好
Sir please,it's for your own good.
你知道什么
Well what do you know.
虽然我知道的不多 但我知道
I may not know much,but I do know this.
坏人得不到女孩的心
The bad guy doesn't get the girl.
也许我不想再做坏人了
Maybe I don't want to be the bad guy anymore.
听见了没
You heard me.
你是谁?
Who are you?
- 给我钥匙 - 不!
-Now give me the keys. - NO!
我的使命是照顾你
My soul purpose in life is to look after you.
我不需要你来照顾
Well I don't need you to look after me.
你...你说什么?
What are you...what are you saying?
- 你不需要我? - 跟你说白了
-You don't need me? - Let me make it clear.
我不需要你
Code-I don't need you.
你知道吗 你知道吗
You know what,you know what.
我打包走人了
Code-I'll just pack my thing and go.
好的!
Code-Fine!
好就好
Code-Fine back.
祝你约会成功
Well good luck on your date.
- 一定会的 - 这毫无意义
-I will. - That doesn't even make any sense.
我懂
I know.
已经很接近了 我能感觉到
I know I am so close,I can feel it.
好吧 我该退一步想想
Okay,okay I just have to take a step back.
等等
Wait a minute.
Titan．
Titan.
Titan是什么?
What's a Titan?
我的顺风耳在燃烧
My super ears are burning.
我只听得见罪犯的声音 你不会这么调皮吧?
I usually just hear criminals.You haven't been naughty,have you?
开玩笑 开玩笑
I'm totally messing with you.I'm totally messing with you.
我叫Titan
The names Titan.
- Titan? - 你的专用英雄守护神
-Titan? - Your very own heroic guardian of pure awesome.
你叫什么?开玩笑的 我知道你的一切
What's your name?Just kidding,I know everything about you.
噢!我带来了一些花
Oh,oh!And I brought some flowers,
不知道你喜欢哪一种 所以我全摘来了
Didn't know what you liked,so I just grabbed you know,all of them.
好吧 你不喜欢花 那就忘了吧
Okay,you don't like flowers.Okay,uh,uh,forget the flowers.
- 你想干吗? - 也许我们能去兜兜风
-What do you want? - Thought maybe we could go for a little flight around town.
- 先了解对方 - 哇!
-Get to know each other first. - WHOA!
这对你来说有点刺激
It's suppose to be very thrilling for you.
你知道自己在干吗吗?
Just what do you think you're doing?
我飞得太快了?
Oh are I moving to fast?
你说得对 在我们相爱之前 应该先救你几次
You're probably right.I should just rescue you a few times before we get all romantic.
啊呀!
Whoops!
接住你 有大英雄守护你真幸运
Saved you.You are lucky to have such a great hero here.
不 谁来帮帮忙?
Oh no.Somebody do something?
对 对 我来救你了
Oh,right,right.Duh!I gotcha.
真好玩 你差点死了 但我救了你
That was fun,you almost died.But I saved you.
- 啊 大楼! - 啊!
-Aaaah,building! - AH!
接住了!
Gotcha!
不好意思 你刚说什么?
Whoo,I'm sorry.What were you saying?
我听不见 被我救你的声音覆盖了
I couldn't hear you over the sound of me saving your life.
放下我 马上!
Put me down,right now!
好吧 好吧 抓紧了
Okay,all right,all right,hold on.
你疯了吗?
Are you crazy?
我想我是有点疯狂...为了你
I suppose I'm,a little crazy...about you.
你是谁?说真的
Who are you?Really.
好吧 准备大吃一惊吧 小姐
Oooh,oooh,right.Well prepare to have your mind blown,little lady.
- 看! - Hal?
-Tada! - Hal?
是啊 这不是很好吗?
Yeah,isn't this great?
没有什么能把我们分开了
Now there's nothing keeping us apart.
不 一点也不好
No,it's not great.
我们的第一次飞行 太浪漫了 就像一对老夫老妻
Wow,our first fight.This is so us,we're like an old married couple.
没有我们 我们永远不可能
There is no us,okay.There will never be an us.
但是我有力量
But,I have powers.
我有斗篷 我是好人
I have a cape,I'm the good guy.
你是好人 Hal
You are a good guy,Hal.
但你不明白为什么...
But you don't understand we need to find out why...
- 现在 - 这样不对
-Right now, - This isn't right.
- 听着 Hal - 你应该和我在一起
-Listen to me,Hal. - You're suppose to be with me.
我在警告你 Hal
I'm trying to warn you,Hal.
是Titan 不是Hal
It's Tighten.It's TIGHTEN,not Hal.
- Bernard． - Roxanne．
-Bernard. - Roxanne.
- 对不起我迟到了 - 你的头发很刺激
-Sorry I'm late. - Wow,your hair looks exciting.
今晚不止是头发很刺激
Hmm,not the only exciting development of the night.
超级大坏蛋创造了一个新英雄
Megamind's created a new hero.
我知道原因
And I know why.
一切都说得通了
It all makes sense now.
他怀念被人踢屁股的感觉 所以创造英雄来对付他
He missed getting his butt kicked,so he created a new hero to kick it for him.
但他为什么会选Hal?
But why did he pick,Hal?
Hal是最不可能被选的人
Hal is the worst possible person you could pick.
这很难理解
Wow,that's a lot to take in.
让我大吃一惊
It,it boggles my mind.
我也很惊讶
I am extremely boggled.
谁踢谁的屁股一定会见分晓
You know,I'm sure we'll get to the bottom of who's kicking who's butt.
但与此同时
But in the mean time.
让我们先享受在一起的时光吧
Let's enjoy each other's company.
抱歉 Bernard 你说得对
I'm sorry,Bernard.Of course,your right,
我应该先喘口气
you know,I could use a breather.
为了Bernard 为你是我疯狂世界中 唯一正常的人
To,Bernard.For being the only normal thing in my crazy upside down world.
为了...正常
To...being normal.
- Roxanne - 怎么了?
-Roxanne. - Yes?
如果我不是正常人
Say I wasn't so normal.
如果我秃了 而且是有色人种
Say I was bald and had the complexion of a popular primary color.
只是打个比方
As a random,non specific example.
你还会对我有兴趣吗?
Would you still enjoy my company?
当然 不能以貌取人
Of course,you don't judge a book by its cover.
或以外表看人
Or a person from the outside.
太让人欣慰了
Oh,that's a relief to hear.
根据人的行为来评判
You judge them based on their actions.
我看起来有点小心眼 不觉得吗?
Well that seems kinda petty,don't you think.
- 你 - 怎么了?
-You. - What,what?
别看着我!
Oh,don't look at me!
只是个技术错误
Just,just a technical glitch.
别看
Don't look yet.
我错了
My bad.
刚说到哪了?
Where were we?
别动
Now,now,hold on.
你!
YOU!
听我解释
I can explain.
你刚才说的那些话呢?
What about everything you just said?
关于以貌取人
About judging a book by it's cover.
先得看看目录好吗?
Well let's take a look at the contents then,shall we?
你毁了都市侠
You destroyed Metro Man.
你占据了城市并让我爱上你
You took over the city and then you actually got me to care about you.
你怎么这么坏?
Why are you so evil?
耍我?
Tricking me?
你想得到什么?
What could you possibly hope to gain?
慢着
Wait a minute.
我不相信
Oh,I don't believe this.
你难道以为我会跟你在一起吗?
Do you really think that I would ever be with you?
没有...
no...
好吧 Minion 你是对的
Okay Minion,you were right.
我...我也没错啦
I was....less right.
我们还是重操旧业吧
We should stick to what we're good at.
做坏人
Being bad.
Minion．
Minion...
你
You there.
就你
Yeah,you.
把黑蟒战袍拿来!
Bring out,the 'Black Mamba'!
好了 Titan 是时候出来耍耍了
Okay,Titan it's time to go down,in style.
我听说又冒出来个英雄
I hear there's a new hero.
敢跟我过招
who dares to challenge my evil.
叫什么来着 Titan?
Where is the one they call,Titan?
有种你就来啊
Challenge me,if you dare.
噢 不 我们要掉下去了
Oh no,we're gonna crash.
太丢人了
This is embarrassing.
莽夫 幼齿
Ballsy and incipient.
愚蠢 没责任心
Boneheaded,irresponsible.
粗鲁!
RUDE!
不专业 说的就是你
Unprofessional,that's what this is.
都市侠会让我干等吗?
Would Metro Man have kept me waiting?
当然不会 人家很专业的
Of course not,he was a pro.
嘿 超级大坏蛋 我正想见你呢
Hey,Megamind.You're actually the guy I want to see.
而且 这儿又不是没门
Also,there's a door here.
你知道我等了你多久吗?
Do you have any idea how long I waited for you?
不 不 不 我完全能理解你
No,no,no,I totally understand what you're saying.
你等会儿行不 我正打算通关呢
Could you just shut up for one second,I'm trying to beat this level.
你有想过要来吗?
Were you even planning on showing up?
这是什么?
What's this?
这是哪儿来的?
Where did you get all this stuff?
都不是我的
It doesn't belong to me.
你偷的!
You stole it!
- 很帅吧 - 不对 不对 你是英雄
-Pretty cool,right. - Oh no,no,no.You're a hero.
衰人才当英雄
Being a hero is for losers.
没日没夜地战斗 战斗 图什么呀?
It's work,work,work twenty four seven,and for what?
我作秀是为了把妹 结果发现 Roxanne根本不想跟我在一起
I only took the gig to get the girl.And it turns out Roxanne doesn't want anything to do with me.
Roxanne Ritchi?
是啊 Roxanne Ritchi
Yeah,Roxanne Ritchi.
我看到她跟书呆子共进晚餐 眉来眼去的
I saw her having dinner,and making googly eyes at some intellectual dweeb.
谁喜欢这种破事
-Ohhhh -Who needs all that noise.
所以我觉得我们应该联手
That's why I think,WE should team up.
你?等等!什么?
You?Wait!What?
我的力量加上你的智慧
With my power,and your big headedness,
这城市就是我们的了
we could rule the city.
- 你要联手? - 我还设计了我们的新造型
-You want to team up? - I even drew up some new costume designs.
- 看 - 造型?
-See -Costume design?
你负责出主意 所以衣服上有个脑子 戴副眼镜什么的
You be the brain so you get a little brain wearing glasses on your costume,or something.
因为我是老大 应该揣上两把坦克剑
And since I'm the cool one,I'll have like two tanks sword fighting.
真不敢相信
I can't believe you.
你滥用这些才能和力量 满足一己之欲
All your gifts all your powers,and you squander them for your own personal gain.
- 是啊! - 不对!
-Yes! - NO!
我才是坏人 你是好人 我干坏事 你来阻止我
I 'm the villain,you're the good guy.I do something bad,and you come and get me.
所以我才创造了你
That's why I created you.
是的 没错 你是白痴
Yeah,right.You're nuts.
- 太空老爸告诉我 - 太空老爸就是我
-Space Dad told me. - Look,I'm your Space Dad.
你应该多跟都市侠学学
You should be more like Metro Man.
你耍我?
You tricked me?
不乐意了?
Oh,don't like that,huh?
还有呢
Well there's more.
那个和Roxanne约会的书呆子也是我
I'm also the intellectual dweeb dating Roxanne.
- 不 - 我们还法式热吻呢
-No. - And we were smooching up a storm.
么么...么么...么么
Mmmore...Mmmore...Mmmore.
等我逮到你 我...
When I get my hands on you I'm gonna,...
来了!我知道
YES!Yes I know.
将我绳之以法 天哪 太怀念了
Bring me to justice.Oh god,how I missed this.
英雄先下手了
And the hero strikes the first blow.
不过恶魔也会有反击
But evil returns with a backhand.
太棒了!
YES!
嘘
Ahh...shhhh.
滚出来 变态!
Come out you little freak!
看我把你打得屁滚尿流
I want to see what that big brain looks like on the pavement.
你入了本大爷的套啦
You fell for the oldest evil trick in the book.
你这个蓝皮蠢货
You little blue,twerp.
来喽!
En Garde!
就是这种感觉
Oh,now that's the spirit.
吃我一招 再来!
Take,that,parry again!
该来点有技术含量的了
Now it's time for some witty back and forth banter.
你先来
You go first.
哟 我不知道这算什么招式啊
Look,I'm not sure where to go with that.
这下是为了你抢走我女朋友
This one's for stealing my girlfriend.
这下是为了太空老爸耍我
This one's for space Dad making a fool out of me.
超级大坏蛋!这下是为了太空老妈
And Megamind!This one's for Space,Step-Mom.
你辜负了她!
You lied to her!
干得好 你打得好 太好了
Oh,well done,I thought that pummeling went really,really well.
我 我有点小建议
I mean,I have a few notes.
- 建议? - 不过不着急
-Notes? - But they can wait.
你可以送我去监狱了
You can take me to jail now.
不 不 不 我觉得停尸房更好
Oh,no,no,no.I was thinking more like the morgue.
- 你死定了! - 哇 哇 哇
-You're dead! - Whoa,whoa,whoa,whoa,whoa.
不是这么玩儿的
This isn't how you play the game.
游戏结束了
Game over.
小飞虫
Brain Bots.
我要休战
I'm calling time out.
休战 休战!
Time out,time out!
小飞虫 启动保险系统
Brain bots.Initiate the fail safe.
没想到吧 大块头?
Guess what,Buster Brown?
这是铜做的 这下你不行了吧
It's made from Copper.You're powerless against it.
可保险了 用来对付...
It's a very safe metal used to defeat...
都市侠?
Metro Man?
你别再拿我和都市侠比了
You,should stop comparing me to Metro Man.
你跑得了一时 超级大坏蛋 可跑不了一世
You can run Megamind,but you can't hide.
我们得救啦 我们得救啦
We're saved,we're saved!
您叫什么名字 新的英雄
What's your name,new hero?
- Tighten - 谢谢您 谢谢
-It's Tighten. - Thank you,thank you.
Tighten解放了我们
Tighten has freed us.
我可没说解放
Oh I wouldn't say free.
应该说 我将带来新的秩序
More like,under new management.
你想干什么
What do you want?
- Titan走上邪路啦 - 恭喜 你又一个天才计划弄巧成拙
-Titan's turned evil. - Congratulations,another one of your genius plans has backfired on you.
门卫怎么会让你上来的
And why did my doorman let you up?
- Carlos - 你想干嘛 别关 别关
-Carlos? - What are you,no,no!
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
你怎么会需要我的帮助
Why do you need MY help?
你是我认识的最有智慧的人
Because you're the smartest person I know.
你不能躲在这儿
Well you can't hide here.
铜应该有用啊 怎么就失效了呢
Copper should have worked,why didn't the copper work?
上一次明明效果超赞的
The copper worked perfectly well the last time.
铜?你在胡说神马
Copper?You're not making any sense.
听着 如果找不到Titan的弱点 他会把整座城市摧毁的
Look,if we don't find Titan's weakness.He'll destroy the whole city.
好吧 要我怎么帮忙
Okay,how can I help?
我们需要找到答案 你最了解都市侠
We need to find answers.You knew Metro Man best.
他有洞穴或私人要塞那样的藏身之处吗
Did he have a hideout,a cave,a solitary fortress of some kind?
任何线索都行
Anything that would give us clues.
我知道一个地方
Well,there is one place I know.
你给了他超能力 难道就不能收回么
You gave him these powers,can't you just take them away?
不行 我忘记把隐形车停哪儿了 解构枪落在车里
I can't,I lost my diffuser gun when I misplaced the invisible car.
那个晚上 你甩了我
The night you dumped me.
让我独自一人
Alone.
在雨中忧伤
In the rain.
- 你回过头吗 - 没
-Did you ever look back? - NO!
- 疼 我的脑瓜 - 我们想我们到了
-Oh,my giant blue head. - I guess we're here.
这儿就是他的藏身之处
So,this is where he hid it.
过了这么多年啊 我的鞋校
After all these years.My old shhool house.
我觉得 我该为那天晚上的事情道歉
You know,I think there's an apology in order,for the other night.
听起来不错 请长话短说
Okay that would be nice.But make it quick.
还有很多事情要解决呢
We have much more pressing matters to deal with.
哇 难以置信 这些东西他竟然全留着
Wow,can't believe he kept all this stuff.
我记得他穿那件披风
Aww,I remember when he wore that.
能专心点儿么
Can we try to stay focused here?
当然 你说的对 要专心点
Yes of course,you're right,focused.
嘿 过来看
HEY!Come over and look at this.
怎么了 发现啥了
What is it?What did you find?
呃...看
Um.....look!
杯子里还有冰块
This glass has ice cubes in it.
对啊 水冷的时候就会结冰
Yes,that's what happens when water gets cold.
不对 我是想说
No,what I'm saying is,
你不觉得没融化的冰块透着古怪吗
don't you think it's a little odd that the ice hasn't melted yet?
人生之一大谜题啊
One of life's great mysteries.
嘿
Hey.
啊~!
AAAAAAAAH!
我们为您带来可靠报道
We now have a confirmed report.
Tighten 我们曾以为的城市新英雄 现在已成为邪恶化身
Tighten,first thought to be the City's new hero,has turned evil.
这座城市从未遭受如此残忍的破坏
The city has never seen this level of destruction.
如果都市侠还活着
If only Metro Man were still alive.
- 你还活着? - 你还活着
-You're alive? - You're alive.
我还活着
I'm alive.
但我们...看到了你的骸骨...
But..we..we saw your skeleton.
- 你应该死了 - 你是鬼魂吗
-You were dead. - Are you a ghost?
你最好给个万分合理的解释
There had better be,an amazing explanation for this.
说啊 幽灵先生
Speak,apparition.
好吧 好吧
Okay,okay,okay,okay.
你们应该知道真相
You both deserve the truth.
事情要从天文台说起
It all started back at the observatory.
Roxanne被绑架了 我要去阻止你
Roxanne was kidnapped,I was gonna stop you.
那天我脑抽了
My head wasn't in the game that day.
我们的争斗就像走过场 所以...
We were kinda going through the motions.So...
我用了超速能力
Using my super speed.
决定让头脑清醒一下
I decided to go clear my head.
随后我意识到 我们一直都在 重复而愚蠢的角色扮演
Then I realized we had done this same silly charade our entire lives.
我想要从这种思绪中摆脱出来
I tried to get my mind off how I was feeling.
但就是钻了牛角尖
But I just felt stuck.
我意识到 虽然我有超能力
I began to realize,despite all my powers,
但所有市民都拥有一样我没有的东西
each and every citizen of Metro had something I didn't.
选择
A choice.
自打我记事以来 我一直是这个城市的傀儡
Ever since I can remember I've always had to be what the City wanted me to be.
但我的梦想怎么办呢
But what about what I wanted to do?
我茅塞顿开
Then it suddenly hit me.
我也有选择权
I do have a choice.
我想当什么就当什么
I can be whatever I want to be.
没人说过我必须做一辈子的英雄
No one said this hero thing had to be a life time gig.
你也不能就这样抽身退出啊
You can't just quit either.
所以我有了个绝妙的主意
That's when I got the brilliant idea...
假死
...to fake my death.
铜抑制了我的力量!
Copper drains my powers!
你的弱点是铜?
-You're weakness is copper?
你的死亡射线从天而降
Once your death ray hit.
我感到前所未有的自由
I never felt so alive.
我从附近的护理学校里借来骷髅教具
So I borrowed a prop from a nearby nursing school.
都市侠终于死了
Metro Man was finally dead.
音乐男就此诞生
And Music Man was born.
音乐男?
Music man?
那样我就不用改标志了
That way I can keep my logo.
- 神马? - 你神马意思?
-WHAT? - 'Cause of what?
我终于自由了 还发现了我真正的力量
Finally I'm free,to get in touch with my true power.
谱写音乐巨作
Weaving lyrical magic.
听听这个
Check this out.
我有双眼可以看见
I have eyes that can see
始终给我指引
right through leaaadd.
- 糟糕透顶 - 非常高兴您还有音乐才能
-That's horrible. - Granted you have talent,
但现在外面有个疯子在破坏 我们的...你的城市
But there's a mad man out there destroying our...your city.
你怎么能袖手旁观
How could you do this?
整座城市的人民都仰赖你
The people of the city relied on you,
但你抛弃了他们 让我们成为刀俎上的鱼肉...他的!
and you deserted them.You left us in the hands of,him!
无意冒犯
No offense.
不 我和你是一边的
No,I'm with you.
听着 我们需要你的帮助
Look,we need your help.
我很抱歉 我真的是
I'm sorry,I really am.
Um 我已经厌倦了
Um,I'm,I'm done.
知道吗 小家伙 有阴就有阳
You know,little buddy.There's a Ying for every Yang.
如果世间存有邪恶 正义必会声张
If there's bad,good will rise up against it.
我花了很久才找到自己
It's taken me a long time to find my calling.
现在是时候了 找到你自己
Now it's about time,you find yours.
嘿 谁需要他
Hey,who needs him.
我们自己可以打败Tighten
We can beat Tighten ourselves.
我说我们回恶魔巢穴 拿上雷射抢
I say we go back to the evil lair.Grab some ray guns,
呼朋唤友 武装起来
hold them sideways,and just go all gangsta on 'em.
我们不行
We can't
就这样?你放弃了?
So that's it?You're just giving up?
我是个坏人
I'm the bad guy.
我不会拯救城市 我不会迎着落日飞去
I don't save the day.I don't fly off into the sunset,
而且我得不到女孩的芳心
and I don't get the girl.
我要回家了
I'm going home.
除非有人伸出援手
Unless someone comes to our aid soon,
一切将会毁灭
all may be lost.
数以千计的市民已经逃离了这座城市
Thousands have already fled the city in a mass exodus.
余下的被迫在家等候进一步的消息
Remaining citizens are warned,to stay indoors until further notice.
当局发出警告 不惜代价撤离市区
Authorities have issued a warning,to stay out of the downtown area at all costs.
Hal!
我猜猜 看到我有多牛逼之后
Let me guess,after seeing how awesome I am,
你终于觉悟了
you've finally come to your senses.
我对你已经没有兴趣了
Well,I'm over you.
我是来阻止你 Hal
I've come to stop you,Hal.
你?哦 好吧 你要怎么做 把我给我报死?
You?Oh,well.Okay,what are you going to do,report me to death?
我会试着劝阻你的
I was going to try reasoning with you.
你和我 我们一起工作 很长时间了
You and I,we worked together for a long time.
我了解你
I know you.
你不了解
You don't know me.
你从不曾花时间来了解我
You never took the time to know me.
这是我们第一次在工作之余见面 也是我快要毁灭这座城市的时候
This is the first time we've hung out socially.And it's when I'm about to destroy the city.
我想要和真正的Hal谈谈.
I want to talk to the real Hal.
我要的是那个喜爱自己的职业 也喜爱吃调味料的家伙
I want to talk to the guy who loved being a camera man,and eating dip,
有些书呆子 却没有Tighten这么恐怖
And being a nerd and being not as scary as the Tighten-Hal.
太晚了!
To late!
超级大坏蛋
Megamind.
你和我还有帐要算
You and I have some unfinished business.
我会等在都市塔 噢 可别临阵脱逃
I'll be waiting at Metro Tower,oh,and just so you don't get cold feet.
Roxanne!
来啊 Roxi 呼唤你的英雄来救你啊
Come on Roxi,call for your hero to come rescue you.
超级大坏蛋
Megamind.
我甚至不知道你在不在听 如果你听到了...
I don't even know if you're listening,but if you are...
你不能放弃
You can't give up.
我认识的超级大坏蛋决不会临阵退缩
The Megamind I knew would never have run from a fight.
即使他知道自己毫无胜算
Even when he knew he had absolutely no chance of winning.
这是你最可贵的品质
It was your best quality.
你必须站出来 就是现在
You need to be that guy,right now.
这座城市需要你
The city needs you.
我需要你
I need you.
Roxanne．
Roxanne.
你有一个小时 别让我等太久哦
You have one hour.Don't...keep me waiting.
典狱长 典狱长!
Warden,Warden!
听我说 你一定要放我走 得有人去阻止Tighten
Listen to me,you have to let me go.Tighten has to be stopped.
对不起 超级大坏蛋 你还有88个终身监禁
Sorry Megamind,you still have 88 life sentences to go.
时间足够你来反省自己的所作所为
Plenty of time to reflect on what you've done.
如果你想听我说?我会说的
If you want to hear me say it?I'll say it.
听好了 发自我内心最黑暗的地方
Here it is.From the blackest part of my heart.
对....不....起!
I....AM....Sorry!
我不吃这套
Not buying it.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
我危害城市数不清多少次了
I've terrorized the city countless times.
创造的英雄却变成了恶棍
Created a hero who's turned out to be a villain.
我骗了Roxanne
I lied to Roxanne.
我最好的朋友 Minion
My best friend,Minion.
我却当作垃圾
I treated like dirt.
拜托 不要让这座城市
Please,don't make this city,
不要让 Roxanne为我的恶行负责
don't make Roxanne pay for my wrong doings.
我接受你的道歉
Apology accepted.
Minion 你这条给力的小鱼
Uh,Minion.You fantastic fish,you.
我们还在等什么?
What are we waiting for?
我们快走吧
We'd better get going.
你骗到我了!
You got me!
好运 伙计
Good luck,fellows.
我们送死去了!
We're gonna die!
等等 什么?
Wait,what?
嘿 废物们
Hey,Metro losers.
这里是 都市塔
This is Metro Tower.
它被认为是我们城市实力的一个标志
They say it's suppose to be a symbol of our cities strength.
但是 对我来说 却象征着 这个女人残忍的撕碎了我的心
But,for me,it's a reminder of the day this woman ferociously ripped out my heart.
我恨哪
And I hate reminders.
HAL!
不要这样
Please don't do this.
我知道你是个好人 Hal
I know there's still good in you,Hal.
你太天真了 Roxie
You're so naive,Roxie.
你看到了所有人的好 即使他们名不副实
You see the good in everybody,even when it's not there.
你生活在幻想里
You're living a fantasy.
没有复活节兔子
There is no Easter bunny.
没有牙仙
There is no tooth fairy.
也没有英格兰女王
And there is no Queen of England.
这是现实世界 你快觉醒吧
This is the real world.And you need to wake up.
你胆敢挑战 超级大坏蛋?
You dare challenge Megamind?
一山容不得二虎
This town isn't big enough for two super villains.
哦 你确实是个恶棍
Oh,you're a villain all right.
但不是最牛逼的那个
Just not a super one.
啊 有什么区别?
Yeah,what's the difference?
演出开始!
PRESENTATION!
我知道你会回来
I knew you'd come back.
是你一厢情愿
Well,that makes one of us.
- 有什么计划? - 主要是 保命要紧
-What's the plan? - Well,mostly involves,not dying.
我 喜欢
I,like that plan.
我失去控制了
I can't control it.
不!
No!
呵 轻而易举
Well,that was easy.
看来还剩一个
Looks like there's only one loose end now.
拜托 还是对公共交通工具尊重点
Please,let's have a little respect for public transportation.
你回来了
You came back.
你说得对 Roxanne
You were right,Roxanne.
我从不该离开
I never should have left.
哇 我 我以为你死了
Whoa,I...I thought you were dead.
我的死 说得太夸张了
My death was,greatly exaggerated.
那么 你就是那个我听到的小流氓
So,you're the punk I've heard about.
噢!
Ah!
对不起 我尽力了
I'm sorry,I did the best I could.
我为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
Minion?
惊喜!呵呵呵
Surprise!Heh,heh,heh.
他才是真英雄
He's the real hero.
超级大坏蛋
Megamind.
要去哪里?
Going somewhere?
监狱吗
Besides jail.
不 不要打脸
No,not in the face man,please.
如果你明白什么是对的 Tighten
If you know what's good for you,Tighten.
离开大都费
You'll stay out of Montrosity.
- 知道了 - 很好
-You got it! - For good.
太狡猾了 兄弟
Pretty sneaky,sis.
我知道只有一个人会说大都费
But there is only one person I know who calls this town,Montrosity.
啊呀
Ooops.
你!
You!
你觉得很好玩吗 嗯?
Bet you think it's really funny,huh?
我们来看看谁才是可笑的
Let's all laugh at the really cool guy,huh.
你不会得意太久的
You're not going to be laughing for long.
隐形车 嘿 记得那个我甩你的晚上吗?
The invisible car.Hey,remember that night that I dumped you?
现在提这个干吗?
You are bringing this up now?
我当时回头了
I did look back.
你回头了?
You did?
你回头了!
YOU DID!
对 你也应该回过头 马上
Yes,and you should look back,right now.
Oh 我懂了
Oh,I get it.
这是你最后一次耍我了
This is the last time you'll make a fool out of me.
我把你变成英雄
I made you a hero.
是你自己搞砸了一切
You did the fool thing,all by yourself.
你太可悲了
You're so pathetic.
不管你站哪一边
No matter what side you're on.
你总是那个失败者
You're always the looser.
有得就有失
There's a benefit to loosing.
你要为你的错误付出代价
You get to learn from your mistakes.
什么?
What?
哦 你是在跟我开玩笑吧!
Oh,you've got to be kidding me!
Minion 如果我还活着 一定要杀了你
Minion,if I live,I will kill you.
好好享受吧
Enjoy your flight.
啊 !
AAAAAAAAH!
超级大坏蛋
Megamind.
嗯 到此为止了
So,this is how it ends.
通常 我都会更新在我的辉煌败绩中
Normally I'd chalk this up to my last glorious failure.
但不是今天!
But not today!
我能说什么呢?
What can I say?
狗改不了吃屎
Old habits die hard.
说再见吧 Roxie
Say bye,bye Roxie.
内好
Ollo.
关于坏蛋 他们永远赢不了!
Thing about bad guys,they always LOOSE!
哦~
Ohhhh.
我们成功了 你赢了
We did it,you won.
最终 我找到了获胜的理由
Well,I finally had a reason to win.
是你
You.
MINION!
没有冷和...热 光明与黑暗
Can't see it's cold and...warm,and dark and light.
是我 Minion
It's me,Minion.
我在这儿
I'm right here.
我们一起经历多少风雨
We've had a lot of adventures together.
你和我
You and I.
是的 Minion
We have,Minion.
我说...
I mean...
大多数以惨败告终 但
most of them ended in horrible failure,but,
今天我们赢了 是吗 主人?
We won today.Didn't we,sir?
对 Minion 我们赢了
Yes Minion,we did it.
谢谢你
Thanks to you.
我们是好人了
Code-We're the good guys now.
我想是的
Code-I guess we are.
哦 我要去 我想...
Oh,oh.I'm going...I think this...
是了 我快要去了...
This is it,I mean I'm going far awa...
哎哟 真爱演啊
Oh,what a drama queen.
我现在感觉好多了
You know,I'm feeling much better now.
我想我只是需要游下泳
I guess I just needed a swim
- 他吓到你了 对吗 - 哇哦 !
-He had you,didn't he. - Whew!
漂亮 Minion 别管他们
Classic,Minion.Don't give them the face.
看他那小脸蛋儿
There he is with that little face.Look at that face.
我们赢了!我们赢了!
We did it!We did it!
- 给力! - 你赢了!
-Fist pump! - You did it!
我们赢啦
We won,we won,we won.
什么 走开点 野蛮人!
What!Get back you savages!
抱歉抱歉 他还没习惯正面的回应
Sorry,sorry.He's just not used to positive feedback.
真有趣 我想命运不是为我们铺好的路
Funny,I guess destiny is not the path given to us.
而是我们自己选择的路
But the path we choose for ourselves.
好的 举起你们的双手
All right,put your hands in the air.
现在交出你们钱包
Now hand over your wallets.
我只是开玩笑
I'm just kidding.
玩笑而已
Just kidding.
不得不承认
I have to admit.
好人 还是有好报的
Being good,has its perks.
看 你穿白色很不错哦
You know,you look pretty good in white.
超级大坏蛋 请你
Megamind,if you please.
嘿 我孩子看不到了
Uh,hey,my kid can't see.
对不起 朋友
Sorry my friend.
真行啊 小家伙 我知道你可以的
Way to go,little buddy.I knew you had it in you.
女士们先生们...超级大坏蛋!
Ladies and gentlemen...MEGAMIND!
大都市的守护者
Defender of Metro City.
知道吗 我喜欢这称呼
You know,I like the sound of that.
上音乐
Hit it!
'坏' - Michael Jackson
Michael Jackson's 'BAD'
我很坏 我很坏 - 别这样
I'm Bad,I'm Bad- Come On
你知道我很坏 我很坏 - 你知道的
You Know I'm Bad,I'm Bad - You Know It
你知道 全世界马上就会知道 谁是坏的
You know,and The Whole World Has To Answer Right Now,who's bad.
你知道我很坏 我很坏 - 别这样
You Know I'm Bad,I'm Bad - come on.
你知道我很坏 我很坏 - 你知道的 - 我很坏 我很坏 就是这样
You Know I'm Bad,I'm Bad- you know it. - I'm bad,I'm bad,that's right.
我很坏 我很坏 你知道的 你知道
I'm bad,You know it,You Know it,You Know,
全世界马上就会知道 就在告诉你一次...
And The Whole World Has To Answer Right Now.Just To Tell You Once Again...
谁是坏的!
Who's bad!
不要走开 后面还有精彩镜头哟^_^
先生 你真的要时常清下口袋哟
Sir,You real need empty pockets often.
哦 这是我疲惫人生中最糟糕的一天
Oh,this is worst day in my tire life.
哦 不是最糟的
Oh,No worst